footballinsider247.com 2018-12-29

# Privacy Policy - Football Insider - Football Insider

**Introduction & General Terms**  
This document (“Privacy Policy”), in combination with the Cookies Policy make up our commitment to protecting personal information we hold about our website users or any other data subject whose personal information we hold. Personal information as outlined in this policy is being processed by PLYP Ltd (“we”, “our”, “us”, “PLYP”). You can find out more about us by visiting Run Good. In the event of any part of PLYP either being sold or going into receivership, we reserve the right to continue to share your data to third parties in accordance with the latest preferences you have provided. You will be informed should any change of ownership occur, and the new owner will manage your personal information preferences.

**Our Commitment to you**  
We are committed to managing & safeguarding your personal information in accordance with current legislation and best practice. Our aim is to be responsible, relevant and secure when using your data. Whenever you provide personal information we will treat that information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. We will process the personal information you have supplied to us to conduct and manage our business to enable us to give you the most appropriate marketing, information, service and products and provide the best and most secure experience. These are what we consider to be our ‘Legitimate Interests’. We endeavour at all times to keep your data accurate and secure, and to honour your data preferences

We operate websites that may contain hyperlinks to websites owned and operated by third parties. These third party websites have their own privacy policies, and are also likely to use cookies, and we therefore urge you to review them. They will govern the use of personal information you submit when visiting these websites, which may also be collected by cookies. We do not accept any responsibility or liability for the privacy practices of such third party websites and your use of such websites is at your own risk.

We may use third party suppliers to provide part of our service to you. In some circumstances these providers may be based in countries outside the European Economic Area whose laws provide for a different standard of protection for your personal information than that provided under UK Law. In such circumstances:

  * We will only transfer your personal data to countries that have been deemed to provide an adequate level of protection for personal data by the European Commission. For further details, see [European Commission: Adequacy of the protection of personal data in non-EU countries.](https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/adequacy-protection-personal-data-non-eu-countries_en)
  * Where we use certain service providers, we may use specific contracts approved by the European Commission which give personal data the same protection it has in Europe. For further details, see [European Commission: Model contracts for the transfer of personal data to third countries](https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/model-contracts-transfer-personal-data-third-countries_en).
  * Where we use providers based in the US, we may transfer data to them if they are part of the Privacy Shield which requires them to provide similar protection to personal data shared between the Europe and the US. For further details, see [European Commission: EU-US Privacy Shield.](https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/adequacy-protection-personal-data-non-eu-countries_en)

If you would like further information about the specific mechanism, used by us when transferring your personal data out of the EEA please contact us

Your personal data will not be disclosed to state institutions and authorities except if required by law or other regulation. Before we release data on this basis, we will ensure that the information is being provided to a genuine and properly authorised investigation.

We reserve the right to revise or amend this Privacy Policy at any time to reflect changes to our business or changes in the law. It is your responsibility to check this Privacy Policy before each use of the Website.

**Who we are**

PLYP is the publisher of Footballinsider247.com

**What Data we collect**

When you visit one of our websites, we may collect both personal and pseudonymous data about you.

When we talk about personal data we mean any information that can identify you as an individual, such as your name and postal address. Pseudonymous data doesn’t identify you as a person but it might be used in aggregate, for instance when you participate in a survey or when we analyse audience interaction with our products and services.

**Data you provide to us**  
When you participate in, access, purchase or sign up to any of our services, activities or online content, such as newsletters, competitions or events, we receive personal information about you. This can consist of information such as your name, email address, postal address, telephone or mobile number, as well as information collected about your use of our services (such as when you enter our sites and how long you stay on them).

**Childrens’ Data**  
If you are the parent or guardian of a child under 13 (“Child” or “Children”), and have provided us with information belonging to a Child, then alongside the Child’s data provided, we may also process limited personal data about you, so we can record your consent to store, process and use this information about the Child to fulfil the service you have purchased or signed up to on their behalf. We may use your contact details to communicate with you about the Child’s use of these products or services. We will never knowingly send marketing communications to a Child under the age of 13. If you believe we have collected personal information about your Child without your consent, you may contact us and request that we remove information about your Child.

**Data we buy from a third party**  
We occasionally purchase data from third party suppliers. The data we purchase is primarily business data. Business data may include but not be limited to a business email address, business job title and business postal address. Such a purchase may result in you receiving communications from PLYP regarding your business sector or business interests without you having directly supplied your information to us. We keep clear records of the data suppliers and provide an unsubscribe option at every contact. If you have any queries concerning the use of business data we hold about you please email us

**Data we collect through your use of our websites**  
We may collect information about how you use our websites or other content online, and the device(s) you use to access the services. This includes collecting unique online identifiers such as IP addresses, which are numbers that can uniquely identify a specific computer or other network device on the internet. Anonymous data will be recorded for the purpose of reporting web traffic statistics, advertisement ‘click-throughs’, and/or other activities on our sites. We may receive information about you from any third parties we may partner with through the use of cookie technologies to personalise advertisements for goods and services (please see **Online Advertising** below for further information) To opt out of receiving advertisements tailored to your interests by our partners, visit the European Interactive Digital Advertising Alliance at <http://youronlinechoices.eu/>

**How we use your data**  
We may use the information you share with us and the information we collect through your use of our sites in the ways described below and as described at the time of capture.

**Legitimate Interest**  
We may process your personal data on the basis of a legitimate interest which may include promoting similar products or services via direct marketing activity, to manage supression and unsubscribe requests received from you, to identify and prevent fraudulent behaviour, maintaining the security of our system, data analytics, enhancing, modifying or improving our services, identifying usage trends and determining the effectiveness of our campaigns.

Whenever we process data for these purposes we will ensure that we always keep your personal data rights in high regard and take account of these rights. Find out more about your rights and how to exercise them here.

**Cookies and how we use them**  
“Cookies” are small pieces of information that a website sends to your computer’s hard drive while you are viewing a website. We use cookies for a number of reasons:

Strictly Necessary Cookies – These cookies are necessary for the website to function and cannot be switched off in our systems. They are usually only set in response to actions made by you which amount to a request for services, such as setting your privacy preferences, logging in or filling in forms. You can set your browser to block or alert you about these cookies, but some parts of the site will not then work. These cookies do not store any personally identifiable information

Performance Cookies – These cookies allow us to count visits and traffic sources so we can measure and improve the performance of our site. They help us to know which pages are the most and least popular and see how visitors move around the site. All information these cookies collect is aggregated and therefore anonymous. If you do not allow these cookies we will not know when you have visited our site, and will not be able to monitor its performance.

Functional Cookies – These cookies enable the website to provide enhanced functionality and personalisation. They may be set by us or by third party providers whose services we have added to our pages. If you do not allow these cookies then some or all of these services may not function properly.

Targeting Cookies – These cookies may be set through our site by our advertising partners. They may be used by those companies to build a profile of your interests and show you relevant adverts on other sites. They do not store directly personal information, but are based on uniquely identifying your browser and internet device. If you do not allow these cookies, you will experience less targeted advertising.

Social Media Cookies – These cookies are set by a range of social media services that we have added to the site to enable you to share our content with your friends and networks. They are capable of tracking your browser across other sites and building up a profile of your interests. This may impact the content and messages you see on other websites you visit. If you do not allow these cookies you may not be able to use or see these sharing tools.

**Analytics**  
The PLYP portfolio of websites uses Google Analytics as its primary solution for tracking website visits, interactions and events. PLYP uses website analytics data to help improve the way we delivery content and online experiences to visitors.

For full details on how Google processes your data please visit: [https://support.google.com/analytics/topic/2919631?hl=en&ref_topic=1008008](https://support.google.com/analytics/topic/2919631?hl=en&ref_topic=1008008)

**Online Advertising**  
Many of the PLYP portfolio of websites show advertising to users. A certain amount of this advertising is tailored to the individual user, as practice known as “Online Behavioural Advertising” which uses cookies to discover general information about the pages you visit. This keeps many of our websites and services you use free of charge. Our advertising delivery systems and partners uses the limited information available to it to serve adverts to you, which it believes are relevant. It does not collect personal information such as your name, email address postal address or telephone number.

From time to time, PLYP may share this aggregated data with our advertising partners. This could mean that when you are on other websites you are served advertising based on your behaviour across PLYP titles or you may be served advertising based on your behaviour on other sites.

Behavioural retargeting is another form of Online Behavioural Advertising that enables us and some of our advertising partners to show you adverts based on browsing patterns and interactions with the site away from our sites.

If you want to opt out of receiving Online Behavioural Advertising this does not mean that you will no longer receive advertising when you are using our sites. It just means that the advertising you see will not be customised for you. If you would like more information about online behavioural targeting and how to opt out of it, please visit [www.youronlinechoices.com](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/) or you can also visit <http://www.networkadvertising.org/>

Our websites uses JavaScript to detect the use of ad blocking extensions for web browsers, we do not store any information on users’ devices and do not process any personal data.

**Links to third party websites**  
When you click on advertisements or links on any of our sites, you will leave that site and go to a third-party site, which is outside of our control. When we place an advertisement on one of our sites, it does not signify that we are endorsing that advertiser’s product or service. We do not accept responsibility for content, have no control over and our Privacy Policy does not apply to these companies, sites or content and if such third-party sites collect personal data, we cannot control how this data is processed, stored or used. We advise that you read their data collection statements, which accompany any registration and their Privacy Policies before you submit your personal information

**Using our websites from outside the UK**  
We use servers located in the EEA to store data. When you submit your details and in whichever country you are situated you agree to the data being transferred to the EEA and processed under the terms of Regulation (EU) 2016/679 (GDPR) including any implementing data protection legislation in the UK. If you are not in agreement please do not add your personal details on the website. PLYP makes no representation or warranty that the content and materials on the Website are appropriate or available for use in locations outside of the United Kingdom. Those who choose to access the Website or use the services from other locations do so on their own initiative and at their own risk, and are responsible for compliance with local laws, if and to the extent applicable.

**How we keep your personal data secure**  
PLYP’s security policies, rules and technical measures have been implemented to protect your personal information from unauthorised or improper use and from accidental loss.

All our employees and data processors that have access to, and are associated with, the processing of your personal information are legally obliged to respect the confidentiality of your data and are bound by contract to do so.

Note that some of our websites provide forums and commenting facilities where you can post information. When you do so, be aware that other visitors may collect any information you make public.

We have put in place procedures to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you and any applicable regulator of a breach where we are legally required to do so.

**Who we share your personal data with**  
PLYP has formed partnerships with a variety of carefully selected companies that we share data with in order to carry out the activities described in the section How we Use your Data. Below is a non-exhaustive list of our key partners:

Advertising Technology Partners:

Taboola, SpotX, JW Player, Snack Media, UnRuly

We may also have to share your personal data with third parties whom we may choose to sell, transfer, or merge parts of our business or our assets. Alternatively, we may seek to acquire other businesses or merge with them. If a change happens to our business, then the new owners may use your personal data in the same way as set out in this Privacy Policy.

**How long we keep your personal data for**  
We will hold your personal information on our systems only for as long as required to provide you with the products and/or services you have requested.

Where you sign up to receive email marketing from us we will retain your e-mail address after you ‘opt-out’ of receiving emails in order to ensure that we continue to honour and respect that request. To unsubscribe from marketing emails at any time, please click on the unsubscribe link at the bottom of any marketing email and update your account preferences. You may also contact us to inform us if you do not wish to receive any marketing materials from us.

In some circumstances you can ask us to delete your data: see ‘Your rights’ below for further information.

In some circumstances we may anonymise your personal data (so that it can no longer be associated with you) for research or statistical purposes in which case we may use this information indefinitely without further notice to you.

**Personal Data – Your rights**  
Under the GDPR including any implementing data protection legislation in the UK you have the rights shown below:-

**Right of Access**

You may, at any time, request access to the personal data that we hold which relates to you (you may have heard of this right being described as a “subject access request”).

Please note that this right entitles you to receive a copy of the personal data that we hold about you in order to enable you to check that it is correct and to ensure that we are processing that personal data lawfully. It is not a right that allows you to request personal data about other people, or a right to request specific documents from us that do not relate to your personal data.

You can exercise this right at any time by writing to us using the contact details set out here and telling us that you are making a subject access request. You do not have to fill in a specific form to make this kind of request.

**Your Right to Rectification and Erasure**

You may, at any time, request that we correct personal data that we hold about you which you believe is incorrect or inaccurate. You may also ask us to erase personal data if you do not believe that we need to continue retaining it (you may have heard of this right described as the “right to be forgotten”).

Please note that we may ask you to verify any new data that you provide to us and may take our own steps to check that the new data you have supplied us with is right. Further, we are not always obliged to erase personal data when asked to do so; if for any reason we believe that we have a good legal reason to continue processing personal data that you ask us to erase we will tell you what that reason is at the time we respond to your request.

You can exercise this right at any time by writing to us using the contact details set out here and telling us that you are making a request to have your personal data rectified or erased and on what basis you are making that request. If you want us to replace inaccurate data with new data, you should tell us what that new data is. You do not have to fill in a specific form to make this kind of request.

**Your Right to Restrict Processing**

Where we process your personal data on the basis of a legitimate interest (see the How we use your data section of this Policy which explains why we use your personal data) you are entitled to ask us to stop processing it in that way if you feel that our continuing to do so impacts on your fundamental rights and freedoms or if you feel that those legitimate interests are not valid.

You may also ask us to stop processing your personal data (a) if you dispute the accuracy of that personal data and want us to verify that data’s accuracy; (b) where it has been established that our use of the data is unlawful but you do not want us to erase it; (c) where we no longer need to process your personal data (and would otherwise dispose of it) but you wish for us to continue storing it in order to enable you to establish, exercise or defend legal claims.

Please note that if for any reason we believe that we have a good legal reason to continue processing personal data that you ask us to stop processing, we will tell you what that reason is, either at the time we first respond to your request or after we have had the opportunity to consider and investigate it.

You can exercise this right at any time by writing to us using the contact details set out here and telling us that you are making a request to have us stop processing the relevant aspect of your personal data and describing which of the above conditions you believe is relevant to that request. You do not have to fill in a specific form to make this kind of request.

**Your Right to Portability**

Where you wish to transfer certain personal data that we hold about you, which is processed by automated means, to a third party you may write to us and ask us to provide it to you in a commonly used machine-readable format.

Because of the kind of work that we do and the systems that we use, we do not envisage this right being particularly relevant to the majority of individuals with whom we interact. However, if you wish to transfer your data from us to a third party we are happy to consider such requests.

**Your Right to stop receiving communications**

For details on your rights to ask us to stop sending you various kinds of communications, please contact us.

**Your Right to object to automated decision making and profiling**

You have the right to be informed about the existence of any automated decision making and profiling of your personal data, and where appropriate, be provided with meaningful information about the logic involved, as well as the significance and the envisaged consequences of such processing that affects you.

**Exercising your rights**

If you wish to exercise any of these rights or simply wish to find out what information, if any, we hold that relates to you, you must make your request in writing by sending an email to us

You can help us to process your request quickly by providing us with information that will help us identify records we hold that relate to you. For example your name, address, email address, telephone number, subscriber id or in the case of information captured via cookies, the IP address of the device you have used.

**Contact our Data Privacy Team**  
If you have an enquiry or concern about the contents of our Privacy Policy or our handling and use of your data, please email the Privacy Team. If you are not satisfied with our response to your enquiry or concern, you may wish to contact the Information Commissioner via their website

If we decide to change our Privacy Notice we will post these changes on this page so that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it and in what circumstances we disclose it.

Changes to this Privacy Policy  
25th May 2018 – New Policy Published
